Luke Stahl

Head of Developer Marketing & Web Developer

Motivated professional with over 18 years of experience in digital marketing, business development, and front-end programming. Skilled in managing projects from concept to completion, designing educational strategies, and coaching individuals to success. An adaptable leader, skilled in working independently and developing opportunities that align with organizational goals. A passionate storyteller dedicated to building superior web experiences.

Technical Skills

Certified Developer
HTML/CSS
JavaScript (Node, React, jQuery)
CRM

Google Analytics
Adobe (InDesign, Photoshop, Premiere)
Social Media
Content Management Systems

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Builder.io | Remote | Head of Developer Marketing

August 2023 – Present

Pangea | Remote

Director, Developer Marketing

October 2022 – August 2023

- Director, Developer Marketing
- Built a product-led growth developer marketing program, resulting in a 16.59-fold increase within the first year.
- Owned web strategy and content management, achieving 56% organic growth with a 22% conversion increase.
- Managed and maintained messaging and positioning, including a newly established category (SPaaS).
- Lifecycle marketing and CRM management.

Contentful | Remote

March 2021 – October 2022

Senior Developer Marketing Manager, Developer Relations Manager

- Led a team of 4 developer advocates, fostering a collaborative and productive work environment.
- Executed developer acquisition campaigns that resulted in 67% signup growth and increased activation rate by 16% year-over-year in 2022.
- Improved developer discoverability through search engine optimization, keyword research, and paid search.
- Managed developer pathways to the product via the website and educational material aimed at enhancing the developer portal and documentation.
- Managed the developer strategy for technical content blogs, knowledge base articles, and starters, contributing to 63% organic growth year-over-year in 2022.

HERE Technologies | Chicago, IL/Remote

November 2018 – March 2021

Developer Marketing Manager

- Executed scalable campaigns to drive growth in the adoption of tools and APIs.
- Achieved 27% growth year-over-year in 2019.
- Global campaign management for self-serve and paid plans driving developer growth.
- Implemented developer-driven email campaigns and monthly developer newsletters.
- Directed input from key partners into marketing programs and integrated multi-channel campaigns (e.g., events, email, paid search, paid social, display, retargeting, and content marketing).
- Website and content optimization, SEO strategy, and CMS management of developer portal.

Northwestern Medicine | Chicago, IL | Senior Marketing Specialist

April 2012 – November 2018

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development Northwestern University	2017 - 2018
Master of Arts in Communications: New Media and Marketing Southern New Hampshire University	2014 - 2017
Bachelor of Science in Communications and Media Studies Illinois State University	2001 - 2006